That was just a dream... right?
In the face of absolute despair
That nearly burned
our hearts away
You still found the
courage to smile
Like you accepted it all
I lost my voice
And the things I wanted to say
But every time I
fell to my knees
I stood up and kept walking
We were looking for
the ideal white future
Our one and only hope
Now I may be left with nothing
But these raging
emotions that have
Nowhere to go
Still, I'll look for a new dawn
With more than one right answer
I won't stop
Until I find it
Winter Days, Where the Heart Is
Were you holding back today?
No.
It felt like you weren't being as
hard on me as you were yesterday.
That is because your
abilities have improved.
They have?
To be precise, your form no
longer has any wasted movement.
Really?
I was only mimicking
his moves, though.
So you are basing your technique
on Archer's style and not mine.
You can tell that?
Of course.
After all, you had no form
of your own to begin with.
I'm sorry. I didn't mean it as
a slight against you, Saber.
I guess he was in my head because
I was around him all day yesterday.
There's no need to apologize.
If Archer's style is
a better fit for you,
it isn't my place to judge.
Um, Saber...
Good morning.
Hey. It's not often
we see you late.
Fujimura-sensei
was pretty irate.
Finally gracing us
with your presence?
Shinji...
I guess you're feeling pretty
badass after what happened.
Still, I'm glad you came.
If you weren't here,
it wouldn't be any fun.
What's up? Not
going to the cafeteria?
I'd like to, but...
Well, see for yourself.
There can be no doubt.
That lady peeks into our classroom—
Nonchalant, yet brazen as can be.
It is clear she waits not for one who does
not come but for one who does not notice.
She looks about to snap, like one who
left a birthday gift for another to find,
only for it to remain undiscovered
by the recipient for the entire year.
Where are you going, Tohsaka?
It's lunchtime, so I'm
obviously going to eat lunch.
Oh, right.
Well, find a nice spot.
I'll be eating in the
student council office.
Wait just one minute!
What, did you forget your
lunch money or something?
I can share my
lunch with you if...
Of course I didn't,
you blithering idiot!
You'll be sitting in
the wind over there.
Sorry.
About yesterday, I mean.
I've used a Command
Spell on Archer.
I ordered him not to attack you for any
reason as long as our alliance stands.
I know it doesn't make up
for anything, but I'm sorry.
That isn't something you
should be apologizing for.
It was my fault for letting him
run off by himself yesterday.
Okay.
If that's what you
say, I'll go along with it.
Besides, I was partly to blame,
and if he hadn't
been there, I...
Let's call it even.
Yeah.
So where's Archer today?
I left him at home.
Oh.
Crap, lunch
break's already over!
Hang out with me for a bit.
Skipping class every once in a
while won't do any harm, right?
Why are you so fixated
on fortification magic?
I've tried several kinds, but
that's the only one I can do.
I can store simple spells,
alter the flow of mana,
and channel it into
various holding places.
Should you be telling me this?
You told me your specialty,
so it wouldn't be fair if I didn't.
I showed you earlier,
but this is my magic crest.
In the Tohsaka family, we pass
down channeling techniques.
Our specialty is the transfer of power,
either within ourselves or to others.
Did you know that the
Matous are a mage family?
Yes.
But Father told me that they're no
longer considered a bloodline of mages.
Wait a second!
You knew that
Shinji was a Master?
Sorry! I just found
out this morning.
I'd written him off as someone
who couldn't possibly be a Master.
What are you going
to do about him?
Attack him right away?
I wouldn't just attack someone out
of nowhere solely for being a Master.
Wow. You could've fooled me.
I only attacked you because
you weren't taking this seriously.
It was an exceptional exception!
Anyway, our enemy is the other
Master that's been hiding at this school.
Let's focus on them for now.
So you're saying there are
four Masters here at school?
Wouldn't there have to be?
Shinji has no power
as a Master himself.
I told him I'd turn a blind
eye if he behaved himself,
so I don't expect
any trouble from him.
Wait, Tohsaka...
Tell me more about that.
Shinji was the one who
approached me, originally.
He said, "Since we're both
Masters, shall we join forces?"
Naturally, I turned him down, but
he wouldn't take no for an answer.
So finally, I said,
"I already have Emiya-kun,
so I don't need you."
Right to his face!
So that's why he was
acting so strangely.
Well, what's the plan, Tohsaka?
Shinji might not be a mage, but
he was the one who put up that field.
You didn't realize?
Oh, no!
Shinji might...
That's great!
This is how
Servants ought to be!
What's going on?
Keep generating mana
within your body, Emiya-kun.
Sakura!
Wai...
She's breathing.
It isn't too late to save them.
We have to find Shinji
and take down this field.
Emiya-kun!
What are these things?
Golems.
A type of familiar!
I'll summon Saber.
You used a Command
Spell yesterday, right?
That means it's my turn.
Emiya-kun...
I beseech you.
To my side,
Saber!
I have come in response
to your summons.
Master, the situation?
It's as you can see.
A Servant has set
up a magic field.
I want to dismantle it
as quickly as possible.
Archer, do you hear me?
I sense the presence
of a Servant on this floor.
No way! Here?
Rin?
Well, if that's what you sense,
then I'm sure you're right.
But I sense the field's point of
origin as being on the first floor.
It's coming from the first floor
even though the Servant is here?
I can't say for sure,
but that's what I sense.
Rin, where is Archer?
We could make a better
assessment with him here.
I'm calling him, but
he isn't answering!
This field cuts us off
from the outside world.
A Command Spell is
our only means of contact.
We should consider this a field
designed to separate Master from Servant.
The enemy is planning to
settle things here, Shirou.
Saber, there's a Servant
on this floor, right?
You handle that one.
We're going to bring
down that magic field.
Emiya-kun?
A risky move, but
the correct one.
Now, while I keep them busy.
Thanks.
Let's go, Tohsaka.
Damn it!
CHEMISTRY ROOM
Very good.
This is how a first-rate
Master does things.
Once this is over, maybe I'll go
check out Emiya's withered husk.
What is it, Rider?
Hey, what's the deal?
How are you able to move?
Stay away, damn it.
I'm warning you,
you'd better stay away!
What the hell?
Rider!
Rider-class Servant...
Caster...
Tohsaka, did you locate
the field's point of origin?
Yes, it's right over there.
- That room up ahead!
- CHEMISTRY ROOM
Damn, they're persistent!
Is there no end to these guys?
Shirou, stand back.
- Ein Körper...
- A corpse...
- Ist ein...
- is a...
- Körper!
- Corpse!
Shinji!
Don't give me any
of your excuses.
I'll make you pay for what
you've done, no matter what!
Y-You've got it wrong!
You've got it all wrong!
It wasn't me! I
swear it wasn't me!
It wasn't you?
I don't care! Take this
field down right now!
If you say no, I'll blow
your sniveling face clean off!
I'm telling you, you've got it wrong!
It wasn't me! She was killed by...
Shinji!
Ouch, ouch...
Tohsaka!
Tohsaka, over there.
She's dead.
Looks like you abandoned
your Servant to survive.
But if you saw the killer's
face, it'll be your turn next.
Th-That's not fair!
I don't have a Servant!
I'm not a Master anymore!
You two are the
ones they'll be after!
That's true.
Even if you still have Command
Spells, you're no threat.
A gnat like you
can't kill anyone.
A g-gnat?
You're calling me a gnat?
Be glad I'm not comparing
you to a harmful bug!
If you saw who
did it, tell me now.
Right now, that's
all you're good for.
Talk!
Which Servant killed yours?
Get bent, dumb-ass!
Y-You're the ones
who should be scared.
After all, you're the
ones it'll come after next!
It's okay, Tohsaka.
They're all still breathing.
They're breathing?
Yeah, they're alive.
All we have to
do is call for help.
Do they need an ambulance for
something like this? Or should we call...
We should call the church.
If we explain the situation to
Kirei, he'll see to everything.
Okay.
I'll call him right away, then.
You were fighting Caster?
Yes, although it was merely Caster's
shadow that controlled the familiars.
I see. Then the real Caster
hasn't left Ryuudou Temple.
Knowing her, she might have manipulated
Shinji to lure Rider into a trap.
Then Rider was killed
through deception?
Crap.
Still, we know that Caster's
Master is someone at this school.
Right...
Tohsaka, if you have
something to say, then say it.
You were really
level-headed, Emiya-kun.
It took me by surprise.
There was nothing
level-headed about it.
If anything, I was
beside myself with rage.
Even so, you were able to
assess everyone's injuries.
I could never manage that.
It was no big deal.
I'm used to seeing dead bodies.
Used to it?
We didn't understand anything
My left hand groped for
things that vanished to my touch
A moral conflict
stays your hand
and tricks you
out of your future
I don't know how
to protect anyone,
and my ideals might
well be pointless,
but I want to live my life
The past repeats before my eyes
Here I will trust the me
that now stands with you
Until my dream
crumbles and withers,
I hope you will carve
out paradise with me
Fight your fate
I'll find out whether
or not he's a Master.
Anyone who isn't worthy of this
battle should be eliminated early on.
You call yourself a hero?
Then are you saying that you
still have the resolve to fight?
The Distance Between Them
Next Time